patternreview.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy Policy at PatternReview.com

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Statement of Privacy applies to the http://*.patternreview.com, https://*.patternreview.com and OSATech, Inc. DBA PatternReview.com and governs data collection and usage. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise noted, all references to OSATech, Inc. DBA PatternReview.com include http://*.patternreview.com and PatternReview.com. The PatternReview.com website is a sewing community and ecommerce site. By using the PatternReview.com website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement. 

**Collection of your Personal Information**  
PatternReview.com may collect personally identifiable information, such as your name. If you purchase PatternReview.com's products and services, we collect billing and credit card information. This information is used to complete the purchase transaction. PatternReview.com may also collect anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your age and gender. We may also gather additional personal or non-personal information. 

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by PatternReview.com. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the PatternReview.com website. 

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data by posting publicly on PatternReview.com, this information may be collected and used by others. 

PatternReview.com encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to and from PatternReview.com so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. PatternReview.com is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the PatternReview.com website. 

**Use of your Personal Information**  
PatternReview.com collects and uses your personal information to operate its website(s) and deliver the services you have requested. 

PatternReview.com may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from PatternReview.com and its affiliates. PatternReview.com may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered. 

PatternReview.com does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. 

PatternReview.com may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. PatternReview.com may share data with trusted partners to help perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to PatternReview.com, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information. 

PatternReview.com may keep track of the websites and pages our users visit within PatternReview.com, in order to determine what PatternReview.com services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customized content and advertising within PatternReview.com to customers whose behavior indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area. 

PatternReview.com will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on PatternReview.com or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of PatternReview.com; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of PatternReview.com, or the public. 

**Use of Cookies**  
The PatternReview.com website may use "cookies" to help you personalize your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize PatternReview.com pages, or register with PatternReview.com site or services, a cookie helps PatternReview.com to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same PatternReview.com website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the PatternReview.com features that you customized. 

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the PatternReview.com services or websites you visit. 

**Security of your Personal Information**  
To secure your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure, PatternReview.com uses third party services to encrypt data using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol while transmitting the information. 

**Children Under Thirteen**  
PatternReview.com does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If you are under the age of thirteen, you must ask your parent or guardian for permission to use this website. 

**Disconnecting your PatternReview.com Account from Third Party Websites**  
You will be able to connect your PatternReview.com account to third party accounts. BY CONNECTING YOUR PATTERNREVIEW.COM ACCOUNT TO YOUR THIRD PARTY ACCOUNT, YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE CONTINUOUS RELEASE OF INFORMATION ABOUT YOU TO OTHERS (IN ACCORDANCE WITH YOUR PRIVACY SETTINGS ON THOSE THIRD PARTY SITES). IF YOU DO NOT WANT INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, INCLUDING PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION, TO BE SHARED INTHIS MANNER, DO NOT USE THE THIS FEATURE. You may disconnect your account from a third party account at any time. Users can disconnect PatternReview.com's access on the My Account pages. 

**Opt-Out & Unsubscribe**  
We respect your privacy and give you an opportunity to opt-out of receiving announcements of certain information. Users may opt-out of receiving any or all communications from PatternReview.com by contacting us here:  
\- Web page: https://sewing.patternreview.com/cgi-bin/notify.pl  
\- Email: support@patternreview.com

**Changes to this Statement**  
PatternReview.com will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. PatternReview.com encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how PatternReview.com is protecting your information. 

**Contact Information**  
PatternReview.com welcomes your questions or comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that PatternReview.com has not adhered to this Statement, please contact PatternReview.com at:

OSATech, Inc. DBA PatternReview.com  
235 Summer Rd, Building 1, Suite 203  
Boxborough, Massachusetts 01719

Email Address: support@patternreview.com  
Telephone number: 9786082224

Effective as of November 16, 2016 

Selected Reviews, Classes & Patterns 

**Online Class**  
Sew a Designer Unlined Jacket   

~~$49.00~~ **$19.99**  
Sewing Class

 **Online Class**  
Bringing Garments to Life   

~~$39.00~~ **$25.00**  
Sewing Class

McCall's 6503  

by: konniekapo...

Other My Own  

by: williamsgr...

SewBaby One Piece Reversible Sundress Pattern  

$8.95[Pattern](https://sewing.patternreview.com/patterns/12005)

Indygo Junction Very Mary Apron Pattern  

$11.69[Pattern](https://sewing.patternreview.com/Patterns/83167)
